What I want to do today is to spend
我今天来这里
some time talking about some stuff that's
是想花点时间
sort of giving me a little bit of
讨论一下过去两年中，
existential angst, for lack of a better word,
让我产生了一些“存在主义焦虑”（没有更好的表达方法了）
over the past couple of years, and
的一些事情。
basically, these three quotes
以下的三段引言
tell what's going on.
基本上表述了我所思考的事情。
"When God made the color purple,
“上帝创造紫色的目的
God was just showing off," Alice Walker
不过是想炫耀而已“ ，
wrote in "The Color Purple," and
这是爱丽丝·沃克尔在《紫色》中所说的。
Zora Neale Hurston wrote in
佐拉·尼尔赫·斯顿在
"Dust Tracks On A Road,"
《公路上尘土飞扬》中说道：
"Research is a formalized curiosity.
“科学研究就是一种形式化了的好奇心。
It's poking and prying with a purpose."
它是有目的的探索和猎奇。”
you know, we have this attitude, well,
大家都知道我们有这么一种态度：
whatever happens, happens. Right?
”该发生的总要发生嘛”， 对吧？
So that goes along with the Chesire Cat
这跟柴郡猫的话意思差不多：
saying, "If you don't care much
“如果你并不在乎
where you want to get to,
你想到达什么地方，
it doesn't much matter which way you go."
那么走哪条路也就不那么重要了。”
But I think it does matter
但是我认为，
which way we go, and what road we take,
走哪条路还是有区别的。
because when I think about design in the
因为当我想到不久的将来时，
near future, what I think are the most
我觉得最重要的
important issues, what's really
真正至关重要的，
crucial and vital is that we need
是我们需要
to revitalize the arts and sciences
让艺术和科学恢复它们原有的活力，
right now in 2002.
就是现在，也就是2002年。
If we describe the near future
当我们描述
as 10, 20, 15 years from now,
10年、15年、20年以后的图景，
that means that what we do today
你会发现我们今天所做的
is going to be critically important,
对将来至关重要，
because in the year 2015,
因为在2015年、
and the year 2020, 2025, the world
2020年、2025年，
our society is going to be building on,
我们的社会将构筑在
the basic knowledge and abstract ideas,
我们现有的基本知识、抽象概念
the discoveries that we came up with today,
和新发现的基础上。
just as all these wonderful things we're
就像我们在TED大会上所听到
hearing about here at the TED conference
的精彩演讲一样，
that we take for granted in the world
现在我们对演讲中提到的事物
right now, were really knowledge
已经习以为常了。
and ideas that came up
但其实这些知识和概念
in the '50s, the '60s, and the '70s.
也就是在上世纪50年代、60年代和70年代才出现的。
That's the substrate that we're exploiting
这些知识也是我们今天做研究的基础。
today, whether it's the internet,
不管是因特网、基因工程、
genetic engineering, laser scanners,
激光扫描仪、导弹、光纤、
guided missiles, fiber optics, high-definition
高清电视、
television, sensing, remote-sensing
传感、空间遥感，
from space and the wonderful
以及我们今天看到的
remote-sensing photos that we see in
空间遥感器拍到的美丽图片，
3D weaving, TV programs like Tracker,
还有三维编织、像“追踪”（Tracker）和“公司”（Enterprise）这样的电视节目，
and Enterprise, CD rewrite drives,
可读写光驱、
flatscreen, Alvin Ailey's Suite Otis,
平板电视和阿尔文·艾利（Alvin Ailey）舞团的“Suite Otis"，
or Sarah Jones' "Your Revolution Will Not
或者莎拉·琼斯的说唱乐作品
Be Between These Thighs," which
”Your Revolution Will Not Be Between These Thighs“
by the way was banned by the FCC,
顺便提一下，后者被FCC禁播，
or ska, all of these things
或者ska。所有的这些，
without question, almost without exception,
毫无疑问、毫无例外的，
are really based on ideas
都建立在多年以前的理念、
and abstract and creativity
抽象概念
from years before,
和创造力的基础上。
so we have to ask ourselves,
因此我们必须得问自己：
what are we contributing to that legacy
”我们要为将来做些什么贡献？“
right now? And when I think about it,
当我开始思考这个问题的时候，
I'm really worried. To be quite frank,
我真的有些担心。
I'm concerned. I'm skeptical
老实说我很担忧。
that we're doing very much of anything.
我怀疑我们并没有做什么有意义的事情。
We're, in a sense, failing to act
从某种意义上说，
in the future. We're purposefully,
我们没有为未来打好基础。
consciously being laggards.
我们有意识的、故意的滞后于社会的发展，
We're lagging behind.
我们落后了。
Frantz Fanon, who was a psychiatrist
精神科医生弗朗兹·范农，
from Martinique, said, "Each generation
他来自马尔廷科(Martinque)，曾经说过
must, out of relative obscurity,
“每一代都应该在相对无知的状态下
discover its mission, and fulfill or betray it."
努力去发现他们的使命，而后或实现或背叛其使命。“
What is our mission? What do we have
那么我们的使命是什么？什么是我们必须完成的？
to do? I think our mission is
我认为我们的使命就是
to reconcile, to reintegrate
让科学和艺术
science and the arts, because right now
重新成为一家人。
there's a schism that exists
因为当前的科学和艺术在流行文化中
in popular culture. You know,
是被割离的。我们都知道，
people have this idea that science
很多人认为
and the arts are really separate.
科学和艺术是两样不同的东西，
We think of them as separate
认为它们之间存在很大差别。
and different things, and this idea was
这样的想法
probably introduced centuries ago,
可能几百年前就产生了，
but it's really becoming critical now,
但现在它变得越来越重要了，
because we're making decisions about our
因为我们每天
society every day that,
都在为社会的发展方向做决策。
if we keep thinking that the arts
如果我们继续认为
are separate from the sciences,
艺术与科学是毫不相干的，
and we keep thinking it's cute to say,
如果我们还认为一个人说“我对这个一窍不通，
"I don't understand anything about this one,
对那个知之甚少。”
I don't understand anything about the other
是一种可爱的表现的话，
one," then we're going to have problems.
我们将会遇到麻烦。
Now I know no one here at TED
我知道在座的诸位不会这么认为，
thinks this. All of us, we already know
我们所有人都已经知道
that they're very connected, but I'm going
这两者（艺术和科学）是紧密联系的。
to let you know that some folks
但信不信由你，
in the outside world, believe it or not,
这个世界上确实有一些人
they think it's neat when they say,
会自鸣得意地说：
"You know, scientists and science is not
”科学家和科学是缺乏创造力的。
creative. Maybe scientists are ingenious,
科学家可能很灵巧，
but they're not creative.
但他们没有创意“。
And then we have this tendency, the career
与此同时，我们也经常听到职业咨询师
counselors and various people say things
或者其他人这么说：
like, "Artists are not analytical.
”艺术家是没有分析能力的。
They're ingenious, perhaps,
他们可能有独创性，
but not analytical," and
但不具备分析能力”。
when these concepts underly our teaching
一旦这样的思想主导我们的教育
and what we think about the world,
以及我们对世界的看法时，
then we have a problem, because we
我们就会有麻烦。
stymie support for everything.
因为我们等于是自绝门路。
By accepting this dichotomy,
一旦我们接受了这种“二分法”，
whether it's tongue-in-cheek, when
不管是否由衷的相信，
we attempt to accommodate it in our world,
当我们试图在现实世界中应用这种法则，
and we try to build our foundation
并使之成为我们构筑一切事物的基础，
for the world, we're messing up the future,
我们就是在破坏未来。
because, who wants to be uncreative?
试问：有谁想成为没有创意的人呢？
Who wants to be illogical?
又有谁希望自己毫无逻辑思维能力呢？
Talent would run from either of these fields
有天赋的人能够出现在任何一边，
if you said you had to choose either.
然而如果你非要逼着他们二选一的话，
Then they're going to go to something
他们将选择另外一个领域
where they think, "Well, I can be creative
并告诉自己："“我可以既有创意
and logical at the same time."
又有逻辑分析能力啊”。
Now I grew up in the '60s and I'll admit it,
我成长在60年代。老实说，
actually, my childhood spanned the '60s,
实际上我的童年跨越了整个60年代，
and I was a wannabe hippie and I always
那时我想成为一名嬉皮，
resented the fact that I wasn't really
常常恨自己年龄太小，
old enough to be a hippie.
当不了名副其实的嬉皮士。
And I know there are people here, the
我知道在座的当中
younger generation who want to be hippies,
也有想要成为嬉皮的年轻人，
but people talk about the '60s all the time,
人们常常谈论60年代，
and they talk about the anarchy
谈及那个时候有多混乱，
that was there, but when I think about
但对我而言，
the '60s, what I took away from it was
60年代留给我印象最深的，
that there was hope for the future.
是对未来的希望。
We thought everyone could participate.
那时候我们认为任何人都能参与（对未来的建设），
There were wonderful, incredible ideas
许许多多的奇思妙想
that were always percolating,
在我们中间层出不穷。
and so much of what's cool or hot today
当下这些很新奇很酷的东西
is really based on some of those concepts,
其最初的构思其实出现在那个时代。
whether it's, you know, people trying to
不管是人们试图使用
use the prime directive from Star Trek
“星际迷航”中的“首要指令”
being involved in things, or again that
参与各项事务。
three-dimensional weaving and
还是刚才提到的三维编织，
fax machines that I read about in my
或者是我从”每周读者“中得知的传真机。
weekly readers that the technology
这些技术和工程
and engineering was just getting started.
在当时都刚刚起步而已。
But the '60s left me with a problem.
但60年代同时也给我带来了一个问题，
You see, I always assumed I would go
我总是想象自己能到宇宙太空去看一看。
but I also loved the arts and sciences.
但我也同样喜欢艺术和科学。
You see, when I was growing up as
你看，我一路走来，
a little girl and as a teenager,
从小女孩到青少年时期，
I loved designing and making dogs' clothes
我一直很喜欢给小狗设计和制作衣服，
and wanting to be a fashion designer.
一直梦想成为一名时装设计师。
I took art and ceramics. I loved dance.
我上过艺术和陶艺课程，我还很喜欢跳舞，
Lola Falana. Alvin Ailey. Jerome Robbins.
喜欢萝拉·法拉纳，阿尔文·艾利，杰罗姆·罗宾斯。
And I also avidly followed the Gemini
我还曾疯狂的迷恋“双子星”
and the Apollo programs.
和“阿波罗”计划。
I had science projects and tons of astronomy
我做过一些科学项目，还拥有大量天文书籍。
books. I took calculus and philosophy.
我上过微积分和哲学课程，
I found myself, my senior year,
我发现，在我大四的时候
chemical engineering major, half the folks
虽然我的专业是化学工程，
thought I was a political science and
但有一半人认为我是学政治和表演的。
performing arts major, which was sort of
其实也对，
true because I was Black Student Union President
因为我那时侯除了担任黑人学生联合会的主席，
and I did major in some other things,
的确还学习过其他的专业。
and I found myself the last quarter juggling
最后一个学期的时候，
chemical engineering separation processes,
我同时做了很多事情，包括学习化学工程分解过程，
logic classes, nuclear magnetic resonance
逻辑课，研究核磁共振光谱，
and choreographing a dance production,
一个舞蹈作品。
do I go to New York City
我是应该去纽约
to try to become a professional dancer,
从事舞蹈行业呢
or do I go to medical school?
还是去上医学院。
Now, my mother helped me figure
最终我妈妈帮我做了决定。
that one out. (Laughter)
（笑声）
But when I went into space,
然而，后来当我走进太空的时候，
when I went into space I carried a number
我随身带了一些东西，
of things up with me. I carried a poster
其中包括一张阿尔文·艾利的海报－
by Alvin Ailey, which you can figure out
你们已经知道他是谁了
now, I love the dance company.
我喜欢那个舞蹈团。
performing the dance "Cry," dedicated to all
献给全世界所有黑人女性同胞。
black women everywhere. A Bundu statue,
还带了一尊本杜的塑像，
which was from the Women's Society
是塞拉利昂的妇女协会送给我的，
in Sierra Leone, and a certificate for the
还有一份颁发给芝加哥公立学校的一份证书，
Chicago Public School students to work to
是用来鼓励那些
improve their science and math,
努力学习科学和数学的学生。
and folks asked me,
人们都问我，
"Why did you take up what you took up?"
“你为什么带这些东西？”
And I had to say,
我回答说：
"Because it represents human creativity,
“因为这体现了人类的创造力“。
the creativity that allowed us, that we were
有了这种创造力，
required to have to conceive and build
我们才能够构思、建造
and launch the space shuttle, springs from
和发射航天飞机。
the same source as the imagination and
这跟雕刻一尊本杜的塑像所需要的想象力和分析能力
analysis it took to carve a Bundu statue,
在本质上是同源的，
or the ingenuity it took to design,
跟设计、编排和表演
choreograph, and stage "Cry."
舞蹈”哭泣“所需要的独创性也是同源的。
Each one of them are different
只是它们借助不同的的表达形式，
manifestations, incarnations, of creativity,
是人类创造力的不同化身和
avatars of human creativity,
不同表现而已。
and that's what we have to reconcile
这就需要我们去调整思维，
in our minds, how these things fit together.
思考这些事情之间的联系。
The difference between arts and sciences
艺术和科学之间的区别
is not analytical versus intuitive, right?
并不是分析能力和直觉的区别。对吗？
E=MC squared required
E=mc²的发现
an intuitive leap, and then you had
需要瞬间的灵感喷涌，
to do the analysis afterwards.
但之后你必须做逻辑分析。
Einstein said, in fact, "The most beautiful
爱因斯坦早就说过：
thing we can experience is the mysterious.
“我们能体验到的最美丽的东西就是神秘感，
It is the source of all true art and science."
它是所有真实艺术和科学的发源地。"
to express the jubilation in life, but then you
并渴望表达生活中的一切美好。
have to figure out, exactly
然而为了达到这个目标，你必须思考
what movement do I do to make sure
究竟什么样的舞步
that it comes across correctly?
才能表达出我想要传达的东西。
The difference between arts and sciences
艺术和科学的区别
is also not constructive versus
也不是建构和解构的关系。
think of the sciences as deconstructive.
许多人认为科学是解构的，
You have to pull things apart.
因为你必须把事物拆开来进行研究。
And yeah, sub-atomic physics
是的，亚原子物理学
is deconstructive. You literally try to
的确是解构的。你确实想要
tear atoms apart to understand
把原子拆开来研究看看里面是什么。
and you remove what doesn't
因为你看到一样东西后，
Biotechnology is constructive.
生物科技是建构性的，
Orchestral arranging is constructive.
交响乐编曲也是建构性的。
So in fact we use constructive and
所以实际上建构和解构技巧的使用
deconstructive techniques in everything.
随处可见。
The difference between science
科学和艺术的区别
are different sides of the same coin, even,
一枚硬币的两面，
or even different parts
或一个连续体中的
of the same continuum, but rather
不同部分。两者其实
they're manifestations of the same thing.
是同一事物的不同表现形式。
Different quantum states of an atom?
是同一个原子的不同量子状态？
Or maybe if I want to be more 21st century
或者按照更加21世纪的说法，
I could say that they are different harmonic
我可以说它们是
resonances of a superstring.
同一根“超级弦”的不同的谐共振。
But we'll leave that alone. (Laughter)
我们还是不那么说吧。（笑声）
They spring from the same source.
它们有着共同的起源。
The arts and sciences are avatars of
艺术和科学是人类创造力的化身。
human creativity. It's our attempt
是人类为了表达
as humans to build an understanding
对宇宙和周围世界的认知
of the universe, the world around us.
而进行的尝试。
It's our attempt to influence things,
也是我们试图影响
the universe internal to ourselves
我们内心世界和外部世界
and external to us.
所做的努力。
The sciences, to me, are manifestations
科学，在我看来，
of our attempt to express
是我们表达和分享
or share our understanding,
对外部世界的理解和体验，
our experience, to influence the universe
去影响外部世界
external to ourselves.
的一种尝试。
It doesn't rely on us as individuals.
它的存在独立于人类个体。
It's the universe, as experienced
它是宇宙万物，每个人都能体验得到。
by everyone, and the arts manifest
而艺术表达了我们的一种渴望，
or influence others through experiences
去跟别人分享，
that are peculiar to us as individuals.
或者影响其他人。
Let me say it again another way:
让我换一种说法：
science provides an understanding
科学帮助我们了解
of a universal experience, and
普遍存在的宇宙现象；
arts provides a universal understanding
艺术则是帮助人们
of a personal experience.
理解某一种个人体验。
That's what we have to think about,
所以我们必须把它们都看成是
that they're all part of us, they're
我们生活中的一部分。
all part of a continuum.
它们都是一个连续体的组成部分，
It's not just the tools, it's not just
它们不只是工具，也不仅仅是科学。
the sciences, you know, the mathematics
像数学、数值
and the numerical stuff and the statistics,
还有统计这样的东西。
because we heard, very much on this
我们在这个讲台上听到过很多演讲，
stage, people talked about music
人们经常说到音乐
being mathematical. Right? Arts don't just
具有数学的特征。对吧？
use clay, aren't the only ones that use clay,
艺术还要用到除了粘土以外的东西，而且其他东西
light and sound and movement.
也要用到粘土、光、声和动作。
They use analysis as well.
艺术也需要分析。
So people might say, well,
有些人也许会说
I still like that intuitive versus analytical
可是我还是喜欢将直觉能力和分析能力的区分，
thing, because everybody wants to do the
因为每个人都想要做
right brain, left brain thing, right?
右脑型和左脑型的区分，不是吗？
We've all been accused of being
我们都曾经被说成是
right-brained or left-brained at some point
“左脑思维”或者“右脑思维”，
in time, depending on who
究竟是哪个类型就要看
we disagreed with. (Laughter)
我们是在跟谁争论了。（笑声）
You know, people say intuitive, you know
人们对“直觉”的解释，
that's like you're in touch with nature,
往往有着亲近大自然、
in touch with yourself and relationships.
了解自己的内心及与人关系亲密的含义。
Analytical: you put your mind to work, and
而“分析能力”，则是要你把脑力调动起来。
I'm going to tell you a little secret. You all
我要告诉你们一个小秘密
know this though, but sometimes people
不过你们也许都已经都知道了。
use this analysis idea, that things are
有时候人们说到分析能力，
outside of ourselves, to be, say, that this
会说存在于我们之外的世间万物
is what we're going to elevate
才是真正的也是最重要
as the true, most important sciences, right?
的科学的研究对象。不是吗？
And then you have artists, and you all
而艺术家呢，
know this is true as well,
你们都知道这也是真的。
artists will say things about scientists
艺术家会说一些科学家的不是
because they say they're too concrete,
他们认为科学家过于具体了，
they're disconnected with the world.
以至于与世界脱节了。
But, we've even had that here on stage,
其实在这个舞台上我们就看到过这种现象。
so don't act like you don't know
所以你们不要假装不知道
what I'm talking about. (Laughter)
我在说什么。（笑声）
We had folks talking about the Flat Earth
我们曾经有---
Society and flower arrangers, so there's
曾经有同仁在这里谈论过地平协会和插花艺术。
this whole dichotomy that we continue
所以这个“二分法”
to carry along, even when we know better.
将是长期存在的，尽管现在我们的知识比以前多得多。
And folks say we need to choose either or.
有些同仁说我们应该“二者选其一“。
But it would really be foolish to choose
但选其一将是一种很愚蠢的做法。
Intuitive versus analytical?
将直觉和分析能力对立起来，
That's a foolish choice. It's foolish,
这是个很愚蠢的做法。
just like trying to choose between
这跟试图在现实主义和理想主义
being realistic or idealistic.
之间划清界限一样愚蠢。
You need both in life. Why do people
这两样东西在你的生活中都是缺一不可的。
do this? I'm just gonna quote
人们为什么这么做？
who's 70 years old so he can say this. He said,
他已经70岁了所以有资格这么说。
"It's always important to distinguish
他说：“把贞洁和阳痿区分开
between chastity and impotence."
是很重要的“。
Now... (Laughter)
（笑声）现在，
I want to share with you
我想跟你们分享
a little equation, okay?
一个小等式。好吗？
How do understanding science
我们对科学和艺术的理解
and the arts fit into our lives
跟我们的生活、我们身边发生的事情
and what's going on and the things
以及我们在这个设计大会上
that we're talking about here
所谈论的事情
at the design conference, and this is
有什么关系呢？
a little thing I came up with, understanding
我得出的结论是：
and our resources and our will
我们（对事物）的理解、我们所拥有的资源
cause us to have outcomes.
以及我们的意志，决定了我们是否有所作为。
Our understanding is our science, our arts,
这些理解体现在我们的科学、艺术、宗教，
our religion, how we see the universe
以及我们如何看待周围的世界。
around us, our resources, our money,
我们的资源、我们的资金、
our labor, our minerals, those things
劳动力、矿产，
that are out there in the world we have
所有那些我们用来创造价值
to work with.
的其他事物。
But more importantly, there's our will.
但更重要的是我们的意志。
This is our vision, our aspirations
这是我们对未来的规划和抱负，
of the future, our hopes, our dreams,
我们的希望、梦想、
our struggles and our fears.
挣扎和恐惧，
Our successes and our failures influence
成功和失败
what we do with all of those, and to me,
影响到我们的行动。对我而言
design and engineering, craftsmanship and
设计和工程、手艺和技术劳动，
skilled labor, are all the things that work on
都是我们为了产生想要的结果，
this to have our outcome,
也就是为了人类的生活质量
which is our human quality of life.
所必需的。
Where do we want the world to be?
我们希望世界走向何方？
And guess what?
你猜怎么着？
Regardless of how we look at this, whether
无论我们如何看待这个问题，
we look at arts and sciences are separate
无论我们认为科学和艺术是各自为政
or different, they're both being influenced
或是迥然不同的，它们都在互相影响着，
now and they're both having problems.
并且都有各自的问题。
I did a project called S.E.E.ing the Future:
我曾做过一个项目，叫做“未来的S.E.E"
Science, Engineering and Education, and
S.E.E代表科学、工程和教育
it was looking at how to shed light on
我想要研究
We got a bunch of scientists in all stages
我们召集了一批处于各个职业发展阶段的科学家，
of their careers. They came to Dartmouth
他们来到达特茅斯大学
what are some of the issues of public
公共资金运用在科学和工程研究
funding for science and engineering
上面的问题是什么？
research? What's most important about it?
在这个问题上最重要的是什么？
There are some ideas that emerged that
讨论中呈现出来的一些问题
I think have really powerful parallels
我认为与艺术领域的问题可以类比。
to the arts. The first thing they said was that
他们谈到的第一件事情是，
the circumstances that we find ourselves in
在我们这个时代
today in the sciences and engineering that
能够让我们在科学和工程方面
made us world leaders is very different
领先世界的所需的资质，
than the '40s, the '50s, and the '60s
与40年代、50年代和60年代
and the '70s when we emerged
以及70年代我们刚刚开始领先世界的时候
as world leaders, because we're no longer
非常不一样，因为我们
in competition with fascism, with
不再需要跟法西斯作战
Soviet-style communism, and by the way
跟苏联式的共产主义竞争。
that competition wasn't just military,
顺便说一句，当时的竞争不光是军事上的，
it included social competition
它也包括了社会竞争
and political competition as well,
和政治竞争。
that allowed us to look at space
正是这样的竞争促使我们把目光投向太空，
as one of those platforms to prove
将太空作为一个平台
that our social system was better.
去证明我们的社会体制更加优越。
Another thing they talked about was the
另一个被讨论的话题是
infrastructure that supports the sciences
如今支撑科学研究的基础设施
is becoming obsolete. We look at
已经逐渐过时。
universities and colleges, small, mid-sized
看一看全国的大学、学院
community colleges across the country,
以及中小型的社区大学
their laboratories are becoming obsolete,
它们的实验室正在过时。
and this is where we train most of our
而这些地方正是我们用来培养
science workers and our researchers,
科学工作者、研究人员
and our teachers, by the way,
以及教师的地方。
and then that there's a media that doesn't
另外，我们的媒体
support the dissemination of any more than
传播的又都是
the most mundane and inane of information.
世俗和无意义的信息。
There's pseudo-science, crop circles,
满眼尽是伪科学、麦田怪圈
alien autopsy, haunted houses,
解剖外星人、鬼屋
or disasters. And that's what we see.
或者灾难，都是这些东西。
And this isn't really the information
这些并不是日常生活
you need to operate in everyday life
正常运作
and figure out how to participate in this
和参与我们的民主建设
democracy and determine what's going on.
所需要的信息。
They also said that there's a change
科学家们还提到了
in the corporate mentality. Whereas
发生在一些大公司身上的变化。
government money had always been there
尽管政府资金从来都是
for basic science and engineering research,
支持基础科学和工程研究的，
we also counted on some companies to do
但我们也指望一些公司能做一些
some basic research, but what's happened
基础研究。然而目前的现状是---
now is companies put more energy into
公司将更多的资源投入在
short-term product development
短期的产品研发上
than they do in basic engineering
而不是基础工程和科学研究中。
And education is not keeping up.
另外，教育也没能跟上。
In K through 12, people are taking out
在K-12(基础教育）阶段
wet labs. They think if we put a computer
传统的实验室正在逐渐被取代。
in the room it's going to take the place
他们认为如果我们放一台电脑在那里，
of actually, we're mixing the acids,
我们就不需要去真正的将两瓶酸混在一起做实验，
we're growing the potatoes.
不需要再去种土豆了。
And government funding is decreasing
还有，近年来政府开销
in spending and then they're saying,
逐年紧缩。于是有人说
let's have corporations take over,
让我们把项目交给公司去做吧。
and that's not true. Government funding
其实这样并不正确。
cost-benefits of basic science and
基础科学和工程研究的
engineering research. We have to know
投入产出比。我们必须认识到
that we have a responsibility
我们作为一个世界公民
as global citizens in this world.
是承担了一些责任的。
We have to look at the education
我们必须审视我们的教育，
of humans. We need to build our resources
我们必须对我们的师资
today to make sure that they're trained so
进行教育，让他们也意识到
that they understand the importance of
这些事情的重要性。
these things, and we have to support
而且我们还必须确保
the vitality of science, and that doesn't
科学研究充满活力。
mean that everything has to have one thing
这并不是说我们投入一分
that's going to go on, or we know
就必须产出一分
exactly what's going to be the outcome of it,
或者我们必须知道研究的结果将是什么，
but that we support the vitality and the
而是我们要鼓励充满活力
intellectual curiosity that goes along,
和好奇心的科学研究。
and if you think about those parallels
你仔细想想，
to the arts, the competition
其实在艺术上也是这样
with the Bolshoi Ballet spurred
与Bolshoi芭蕾舞团的竞争
the Joffrey and the New York City Ballet
刺激了Joffrey以及纽约芭蕾舞团
to become better.
更好的发展
Infrastructure museums, theaters,
全国范围内的基础设施
movie houses across the country
诸如博物馆、戏院、电影院
are disappearing. We have more
正在消失。我们的电视台
television stations with less to watch,
越来越多，但可看的内容却越来越少。
we have more money spent on
我们的钱都花在
rewrites to get old television programs
把旧的电视节目
in the movies.
改编成电影。
We have corporate funding now that,
我们有了企业的资助
when it goes to some company, when it
但有些公司拿这个钱
goes to support the arts, it almost requires
来扶持艺术的时候，几乎要求
that the product be part of the picture
他们的产品必须出现在
that the artist draws, and we have
艺术作品中。
stadiums that are named over and over
我们的体育场一而再、再而三的
again by corporations.
被企业冠名
In Houston, we're trying to figure out
在休斯敦，我们试图搞清楚
what to do with that Enron Stadium thing.
那个“安然”体育场到底是个什么名堂
(Laughter) And fine arts and education
（笑声）学校的艺术教育
in the schools is disappearing, and we have
也在退化
a government that seems like it's gutting
我们的政府看上去好像要
the NEA and other programs,
取消NEA和其他一些项目
so we have to really stop and think,
所以我们必须停下来想想
what are we trying to do
我们到底需要如何
with the sciences and the arts?
发展科学和艺术
There's a need to revitalize them.
的确有必要向它们重新注入活力
We have to pay attention to it. I just want
我们必须开始关注这个了。
to tell you really quickly what I'm doing.
我想很简单的告诉你们我现在在做什么
(Applause)
（掌声）
I want to tell you what I've been doing
先说说我以前都做过些什么
a little bit since... I feel this need
因为我觉得有必要
to sort of integrate some of the ideas
需要将以前的一些想法
that I've had and run across over time.
融合进来
One of the things that I found out
我领悟到的事情之一
is that there's a need to repair
就是有必要修复
the dichotomy between the mind and body
脑力和体力活动的 “二分法”
as well. My mother always told me,
我的母亲总是告诉我说
you have to be observant, know what's
你必须具有一定的观察力
going on in your mind and your body,
时刻了解你的大脑和身体所从事的活动。
and as a dancer I had this tremendous
作为一个舞者
faith in my ability to know my body,
我对读懂自己身体的能力极为自信，
just as I knew how to sense colors.
就像我对色彩的敏感度一样。
Then I went to medical school, and I was
后来我上了医学院
supposed to just go on
人们告诉我应该
what the machine said about bodies.
听从那些医学仪器对于身体的检测结果。
You know, you would ask patients
我们都会问病人一些问题
questions and some people would tell you,
他们会回答，但是有些人会告诉你
"Don't, don't, don't listen to what
“千万不要听病人的话。”
the patients said." We know that patients
但我们知道病人
know and understand their bodies better,
更加了解和懂得自己的身体。
but these days we're trying to divorce them
但近几年来我们开始告诉他们
from that idea. We have to reconcile the
不要听从自己的感受。
patient's knowledge of their body
我们必须将病人对自己身体的知识
with physician's measurements.
和机器的测量结果结合起来。
We had someone talk about
我听到有人谈到
measuring emotions and getting machines
要用机器检测情绪，让机器去
to figure out what, to keep us
搞清楚如何才能让人们
from acting crazy. Right?
保持理智。对吧？
No, we shouldn't measure,
这是不对的，我们不应该测量这个。
we shouldn't use machines
我们不应该用机器
to measure road rage and then do
来测量公路暴力行为，
something to keep us from engaging in it.
然后想办法不让我们发怒。
Maybe we can have machines help us
也许我们可以让机器帮助我们
to recognize that we have road rage and
识别这种暴怒行为，
then we need to know how to control that
然后我们要在不需要机器帮助
without the machines. We even need to be
的情况下去控制这种暴怒，
What I'm very concerned about
我非常关注的，
is how do we bolster our self-awareness
是如何提高我们人类
as humans, as biological organisms?
作为一个生物机体的自我意识。
Michael Moschen spoke of having to teach
Michael Moschen谈到过如何
and learn how to feel with my eyes,
才能用眼睛来触摸，
We have all kinds of possibilities to use
我们有各种各样不同的方式
our senses by, and that's
来使用我们的感官，
what we have to do.
这就是我们需要做的。
That's what I want to do, is to try to use
这也是我想要做的，
bioinstrumentation, those kind of things
就是使用生物仪器和类似产品
to help our senses in what we do,
帮助我们感知我们正在做的事情。
and that's the work I've been doing now as
这也是我的公司
a company called BioSentient Corporation.
“生物感知（BioSentient）”所在做的事情。
I figured I'd have to do that ad, because
我不得不做这个广告，
I'm an entrepreneur, because entrepreneur
因为我是一个创业者
says that that's somebody who does what
而创业者总说他们做着
they want to do because they're not broke
自己想做的事情，而且还没有
enough that they have to get a real job.
破产到一定要找一份工作的份上。
(Laughter) But that's the work I'm doing
（笑声）我试图通过“生物感知”
with BioSentient Corporation trying to figure
这个公司回答的问题
out how do we integrate these things?
就是我们如何将这些事情结合起来？
Let me finish by saying that
让我做如下总结：
my personal design issue for the future
我个人对未来的设计计划
is really about integrating, to think about
就是关于“结合”，
that intuitive and that analytical.
把直觉思考和分析思考结合起来，
The arts and sciences are not separate.
艺术和科学不是相互独立的。
High school physics lesson before you
在我们离开之前，说一下高中物理课
leave. High school physics teacher used to
物理老师经常举起一个球，
hold up a ball. She would say this ball
说这个球
has potential energy, but nothing
有势能，
will happen to it, it can't do any work
但它不能做功，
until I drop it and it changes states.
除非我让它落下从而改变它的状态。
I like to think of ideas as potential energy.
我喜欢把新的想法比作势能，
They're really wonderful, but nothing
它们的确很精彩，
will happen until we risk
但如果不将它们付诸实践
putting them into action.
就什么都不会发生。
This conference is filled
这个大会上，
with wonderful ideas.
精彩的点子层出不穷，
We're going to share lots of things
我们分享很多的东西，
with people, but nothing's going to happen
但若没人去实践，
until we risk putting those ideas into action.
就不会有任何成果。
We need to revitalize the arts and sciences
我们需要让艺术和科学重现活力，
of today, we need to take responsibility
我们必须承担起对未来的责任。
for the future. We can't hide behind saying
我们不能躲起来说
it's just for company profits,
这只是为了公司利益，
or it's just a business, or I'm an artist
或者只是一桩生意，
or an academician.
或者说我是个艺术家，或学者。
Here's how you judge what you're doing.
你应该这样去判断你所做的事情，
I talked about that balance between
我提到了直觉和分析能力
intuitive, analytical.
之间的平衡。
Fran Lebowitz, my favorite cynic,
弗兰·李伯茨是我最钟爱的犬儒主义者，
she said the three questions
她曾经提到过
of greatest concern, now I'm going to
三个对设计来说
add on to design, is,
最重要的事情：
"Is it attractive?"
首先，是否吸引人？
That's the intuitive.
这是直觉思维；
"Is it amusing?" The analytical.
其次，是否有趣？
"And does it know its place?"
最后，是否了解自己所处的位置？
The balance. Thank you very much.
也就是平衡。
(Applause)
（掌声）